("Future Me Hates Me"
by The Beths playing)
♪ I never wanted to
I didn't wanna fall ♪
♪ I don't believe that love's
a good idea at all ♪
♪ Oh, this well-designed woe
♪ Everyone that I know is broken
and has fell for it before ♪
♪ And sometimes
I think I'm doing fine ♪
♪ Oh, then the walls
become thin ♪
♪ And somebody gets in
I'm defenseless ♪
♪ But it won't happen again ♪
♪ It's a well-designed woe
Everyone that I know is broken ♪
(man) I'm sorry.
I'm a little confused.
Have you worked
in a veterinary office before?
Because I'm not seeing it here.
I see you've worked
in several bars.
Music venues, actually.
Uh... I mean, they all...
You know, they served alcohol
but it was really
all about music
at that time in my...
I'm sorry. That... (chuckles)
Doesn't matter. Not important.
Um... Yeah.
The vet tech work is there.
-It's in the margins?
-(paper flips)
I, uh... Yeah, my printer's
offline right now
so I just updated it manually
with a pen.
You can think of it
as, like, artisanal. (laughs)
Anyway, so, uh,
the clinic was off Aurora?
It's a busy place and I...
I just... I loved it there
and they loved me.
I mean, for the most part.
(sighs)
You can call over and ask.
Um...
Just make sure you call
after 6:00 p.m.
and ask for Becky Ferndale.
She's the night shift
manager there.
Um... Yeah.
She really runs the place
despite what anyone else
might say.
(sighs)
Anyway, I, uh, I renewed
my vet tech license recently,
so that's all up to snuff,
and, um, I am ready to work.
You don't have a college degree.
You need a college degree
to stick a thermometer
up a dog's ass?
Well, it's more
about interpersonal skills.
(splutters)
I know what it's about.
(man sighs)
You know, I-I'm...
I'm really running out
of options here
and, uh, you know,
I-I need to work. I'll...
(sighs)
I'll pretty much do anything.
I'm afraid we're-we're looking
for someone
with more consistent
experience at this time.
I got consistent experience
with being screwed over
by assholes.
-Does that count?
-(man sighs)
-Thanks for coming by.
-Yeah. Thanks for saying
the opposite of what you mean.
(chuckles)
Is that what they teach you
in college?
Two hundred grand well spent.
(dogs barking)
(dogs whimpering)
Oh, shit. Shit.
(indistinct chatter)
(line ringing)
Hi!
You said 5:00.
Sorry I'm late.
-I'm slammed at work today.
-It's okay.
Dad's grilling steaks
for dinner,
so I can only talk for a minute.
Ave, I've been thinking about
you and the contest all day.
How was it?
Horrible.
I got fourth.
It's total bullshit.
I did a perfect Squirtle
from Dark Souls II
and they didn't even get it.
Of course.
They're small time,
you're a cosplay queen.
(Avery) Stop pretending
you know about it.
If I can't even win
a local contest,
I'll never make it
to masquerade level
and I really want to compete
in front of Yaya Han.
Yaya who?
Yaya Han.
She's a legend.
You should see her calendar.
I really want to meet her.
I, um...
I had this idea that maybe
I could start a business
where I make costumes
for other people.
I've been getting pretty good
at sewing and--
Ave, I know how important
this is to you
and I want to help.
(sniffs)
You know, as soon as I pay off
my vet school loans--
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, I, uh...
We can talk about this
at Christmas
when I come visit.
I wanna invest
at ground level
whatever creative, crazy shit
you're doing.
(sighs) You're busy.
I gotta go. I'll see you later.
Wait, don't hang up. Avery!
(sighs)
(waitress clears throat)
(bright, whimsical music plays)
(distant siren blaring)
Shit.
Okay.
(car starting)
(car horn honking)
(man)
The safe lot is full tonight.
(woman)
Is there anything you can do?
(man) No, I can't do anything.
I'm sorry.
-It's just full.
-Been waiting for hours!
Sorry, ma'am.
We're full tonight.
(sighs) I've been coming here
three weeks.
What do you mean?
The city closed the SoDo lot,
moved half of us
up here today.
You couldn't let me know sooner?
Where am I supposed to go?
At least you have your car.
(car starting)
(sighs)
(contemplative music playing)
(indistinct chatter)
(clicks)
Yeah. I see you, Yaya Han.
(music fades)
(dramatic instrumentals
slowly build)
(jarring dramatic music plays)
(banging)
-(loud banging)
-(gasps)
-No!
-(banging)
(grunts)
(man) Just you in there, ma'am?
Who's that?
Oh, shit.
(scoffs) Jesus!
SRT, really?
(man) You look familiar.
Yeah. Yeah, I get that a lot.
I'm not Sheryl Crow.
-Sorry.
-No, I busted you before.
Busted me? For what?
Vehicular loitering.
It's a crime.
King County Ordinance 1202.
You're not a cop.
No, but I've been deputized
by the Seattle Police Department
to combat homelessness.
My daughter used to get
a wing pin from the pilot.
It didn't mean that she could
fly the fucking plane.
Okay. You can't sleep here.
-I'm calling this in.
-Oh, wow.
Oh, look at you. (chuckles)
Who are you gonna call?
Batman? Green Goblin?
Peet's Coffee for matcha?
I don't make the laws, ma'am,
I just enforce them.
Yeah, you don't
enforce them either.
-(man) Kaplan dispatch, please.
-You don't do shit.
Oh, you're gonna have me towed?
-You leave me no choice.
-There's always a choice.
(car starting)
(man over radio)
Go ahead. You got a license?
(man) Okay. Well, hold on.
Oh, no. She's leaving.
Alright, let's head over
to Home Depot.
(man in voice-over) I thought
it was safer for my dog
to shit in my own apartment...
than risk arrest from the DEA,
who I was certain was camped out
across the street.
After a particularly speedy
batch of cocaine,
that's when I knew
I needed help.
That said,
it had to get even worse
before I could bring myself
to a meeting.
(liquid pouring)
It's good to see you, Amanda.
I liked your share.
Whenever you're ready,
we'd love to hear you share.
(Amanda chuckles)
I'm good listening.
Works for me.
(tires screech)
Shit.
So you have a vet tech license
but no college degree.
Hi.
Yeah, uh...
College wasn't really
an option for me.
Well, our clients
are really particular
about who handles their dogs.
Steve Jobs didn't finish college
-and he turned out okay.
-(dog wheezing)
-Yeah.
-Has he always been making that noise?
Don't touch my dog, please.
This is poor little Microchip.
-Aw.
-(chuckles) He has allergies.
The brachycephalic usually do.
You know what can really help?
Just a little eucalyptus oil
in their collar.
A little tip, it really opens up
the passages.
Wow.
And then, um, over here we have
the wonderful Edwina
who does our puppy massages.
And, um, she is very popular.
(laughs)
New appointments open up
at noon on Mondays.
Oh.
Can I be reincarnated as a dog?
(both laugh)
-Uh, you have a car, right?
-Mm-hmm. Yeah, sure do.
Okay, um, we can start you
on pick-up duty Monday morning,
-Okay.
-Yeah.
Oh, and I said "pick-up duty"
which we also do...
-a lot of here, so.
-(Amanda laughs)
Welcome to the team.
Oh.
Thank you.
(both chuckle)
Get the... get the photo before
the dog jumps out of the tub.
-Smile.
-(dog pants)
Your owner's gonna love this.
(upbeat music playing)
(tense music plays)
(music intensifies)
(murmurs) Fuck!
No! Fuck! Fuck!
Goddamn it!
-(exhales)
-(line ringing)
(exhales)
-(man on phone) Seattle PD.
-Yes, I'd like...
(man on phone) Hello?
Ma'am? Ma'am?
-Hello?
-Yes, I'd like to report a s...
Car? Stolen car, please?
(man on phone)
Give me your location.
I am...
A stolen car! I'm off of Aurora!
-North of Aurora!
-License plate?
Yes! Yes! ADQ-377!
-You call me when--
-ADQ-377?
Amanda Ogle.
(dramatic beat)
Yeah.
(indistinct chatter)
(somber music building)
(faint siren blares)
(distant horns honking)
(contemplative music playing)
(phone rings)
(woman on phone)
Hello, is this Amanda Ogle?
Yes. Yes, that's me.
(woman on phone) We found
your blue Toyota Camry.
-Yes, yes. That's my car.
-License plate ADQ-377?
(sighs) Oh, God. Yes.
Yes. Uh, yes. Where is it?
(man) Get the cars ready
for transport to auction.
-(truck backup alarm beeping)
-(dog barking)
-Are you Cliff?
-Yeah.
Hi. We spoke on the phone.
I'm Amanda. You have my car.
It's right out the front.
'91 Camry?
-Blue one?
-Right.
Okay, you gonna be paying
by cash or charge?
(indistinct radio chatter)
-(Cliff clears throat)
-For what?
Well, you have to pay the fine
to get your vehicle released.
Okay, uh, how much?
Well, it's a $150
initial towing charge
plus $50 storage fee, so $200.
(scoffs)
-Two hundred dollars?
-Yeah.
Come on, man. I...
Uh... Oh, wait. Actually...
Well, it's been
two calendar days,
so it's 250 plus tax
which brings it to...
Ba-dum-ba!
...$273.20.
Two hundred and seventy-three--
I have to pay that
to get my stolen car back?
-Mm-hmm.
-Are...
Are you serious?
Why do I have to pay the money?
Well, I can't release
any vehicle without payment.
-(clears throat)
-But the car was stolen. It...
Yeah. Well, you gotta take
that up with the police.
My car is right there. Please?
Can I, like, give you $20
and then we can just, like,
forget this happened
-and I can just take the car?
-It's too late.
It's already
in the system, okay?
I do that, I lose my job.
-My bosses don't screw around.
-Please.
-Please. It's right there!
-There's nothing--
-There's nothing I can--
-It was stolen.
It's not up to me.
I'm not the boss. I'm sorry.
Please, please, please.
-Please don't cry.
-Please.
(sighs)
(sighs) Can I get a few things?
(exhales)
Okay.
What's with the sleeping bag?
-I'm an REI rep.
-Mmm.
And the silverware?
(sighs) I moonlight
at Sur La Table.
Oh, geez.
I'm sorry. There's...
There's really nothing I can do.
Oh, no.
I don't need your pity, pal.
This ain't over.
(somber music playing)
(man) Real Change?
Real Change?
Have a good day.
(cash register beeps)
Thank you.
(distant siren blaring)
(line ringing)
(phone vibrating)
I'm going to bed.
-Hey, Mom.
-Hi, honey.
Sorry I missed your call.
Everything okay?
(Avery)
Yeah, why wouldn't it be?
Where are you?
What are you up to?
I just had dinner
with a friend and...
Oh, I checked out Yaya Han.
She has very cool style.
Um, I'm gonna get back
to my sewing.
No, no. Let's talk a little.
I wanna catch up more.
What are you sewing?
I picked out a pajama top
-at a vintage shop...
-Cool.
...and I'm gonna turn it
into a skirt with some pockets.
Uh, 'cause if I complete
three more costumes,
then I'll be a journeyman.
I'm really sick
of being a novice.
I just want a little respect.
(chuckles)
(sighs deeply) Utah sucks.
I wish...
I know.
I know. It's...
complicated.
You don't know.
You don't know how hard it is.
I mean, you're off
somewhere cool
doing whatever you want.
Yeah, uh... Seattle's cool.
I get a little lonely but...
(clears throat)
...I'm looking forward
to Christmas.
It's been so long. I...
(sniffles) ...miss you.
I miss you too.
I'm gonna get back
to my projects,
but call me tomorrow.
Okay.
(Avery) Bye.
(sighs)
(indistinct shouting)
(fog horn blows)
(sniffles)
-(shouting continues)
-(can rattles)
(loud, discordant traffic noise)
(tense musical stinger)
(man) How'd you sleep?
I only ask because that's
my bench you're sleeping on.
Now, normally, I'd charge a fee
but since you look new...
-I'll waive my usual tax.
-(Amanda) Your usual tax?
You wanna sleep on this strip,
it's three bucks a night.
(sighs)
-People pay for that?
-This ain't Renton.
You've got to pay
for this kind of view. (laughs)
Don't have to be money neither.
Could be, um, booze,
-sex...
-(scoffs)
...Arby's.
That's disgusting.
(clears throat)
People sleep with you
for this bench?
Not yet, but I'm hoping.
I'm good. (clears throat)
So you just slumlord
these city benches?
(man) I'm a computer engineer
by trade.
Came up from the Bay Area
a couple years ago
to work at Amazon.
Got some disciplinary issues
and now I sleep in their boxes.
What about you?
How's a pretty woman like you
end up homeless?
Oh, I am not homeless, pal.
I just had a bad night.
Right, right. Me neither.
Just waiting for Melinda Gates
to call
and put me
on her advisory board.
(fast-paced dynamic music plays)
(man) Thanks.
-Can I help you?
-Yes.
I'd like to sue Kaplan Towing.
Excuse me?
I was reading this thing
on my phone.
It's in the Second
Restatement of Torts,
and it basically says that
I have grounds for damages.
We really don't do that here.
We process parking citations.
My car was stolen.
It was taken on a joy ride or
who knows what by some criminal
and they ditched it
and it's been towed.
And now Kaplan
are charging me for--
Your citation should arrive
in the mail
within seven
to ten business days.
Okay, so about that.
I'm in between places right now.
So no address?
Nothing conventional, no.
Fill this out
and bring it back Monday.
(slow dramatic music plays)
(phone dings)
(Alyssa) Hey, it's Alyssa
from Velvet Dog.
I'll see you Monday at 9:00 a.m.
Please be on time.
A lot of dogs waiting.
Okay. Bye.
Goodnight.
This one's ready
for their photograph.
(dog whimpers)
You need a current valid
street address
to file a complaint
for proper notice.
(sighs) Three hours in line
for you to tell me the sa--
Um...
What if I don't have one?
Then I'm afraid
I can't help you.
You can try over in Window 7G--
Oh, oh! I just thought of it.
I just thought of it.
(pen scratching)
That's your valid
current address?
Yes. That is a valid
current address
where I can get mail and... Yes.
(grunts, exhales)
So when can I get in front
of a judge?
Is there anything today, ma'am?
(laughs)
This isn't Law & Order.
There's a procedure.
It takes time.
I know but I don't have time.
If I could just get
in front of a judge,
and I could explain
my situation,
I'm really not at fault here
and the longer I take--
(man) Hurry up, lady.
What are you doing up there?
Uh, I'm just catching up
with some friends.
What the fuck do you think
I'm doing? Jesus!
The judge can see you
on December 18.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
That's way too far away.
I-- Uh... Oh, God!
I'm not gonna make it that far.
I really...
Uh, I...
I can't afford to pay the fine
and I need the car.
I'm supposed to be
at a job today that requires it
and also I... I'm...
...I'm currently living in the
car. It's not forever.
It's just my situation
that I'm...
I'm currently in.
(sighs)
I'll see what I can do.
Have a seat.
Okay, thank you.
I can't promise anything.
(softly) Thank you.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
(indistinct chatter)
(vending machine rumbles)
-Hi!
-(gasps)
Sorry. Um...
-God.
-I heard you in line earlier.
Well, saw you and heard you,
rather. Um...
Here.
My name is Kevin Eggers.
I work for the Northwest
Consumer Law Center.
We file claims under
the Consumer Protection Act.
We're a non-profit.
I'm a lawyer.
Anyway, I overheard
what you're going through
and can I just say,
you are the exact reason
why I went to law school.
(chuckles)
Uh, I'm why you went
to law school?
Not you specifically, obviously.
My mission
is to help people like you
fight corporate bullies.
(inhales) Oh.
People like me?
Hmm. What exactly
does that mean?
Okay, I can hear now
how, from your perspective,
that could be construed
as patronizing.
Um...
My goal is to use what I know
about the intersection
of civil bureaucracy
and state law
to help people in situations
like yours
be more successful
in their brave efforts.
How old are you?
Uh, 24. Almost 25.
My car is older than you.
-(laughs)
-(Terri) Miss Ogle?
We can get you in next Monday
at 2:00 p.m.
-Is that gonna work?
-Oh, yeah. That's perfect.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Thanks, kid,
but "people like me,"
we actually know
how things work.
We know all too well.
Look, I didn't mean
to offend you.
Miss Ogle.
I really think I can help.
(whimsical music playing)
(munches)
Sorry, we're at capacity.
Come back tomorrow.
-Oh, come on.
-Be safe.
No, please, please, please.
-I was here last night.
-Sorry.
I just need a bed.
Look, you're not gonna find
anything downtown.
Bellevue will probably
just bus you away.
But there's a place
in the U District.
They may have a bed.
But you're gonna have to hustle.
The lady who runs it
is pretty tough.
Okay. Okay, you got an address?
-Yeah.
-Thank you.
(fast-paced dynamic
music playing)
Sorry, I think I'm lost.
Oh, through there?
Okay. Thank you.
Hi.
-Hi!
-Uh... (chuckles)
If you're looking for a bed,
you're too late. We close at 7.
I know. I know.
The traffic
was a nightmare getting here
and the bus was also late.
It's not my fault. I...
was coming from the other side--
This is a high bar shelter,
honey.
We run on rules, not excuses.
No alcohol, no narcotics,
no animals.
Oscar! Here, kitty.
Psp! Psp! Psp!
Oscar? Have you seen my kitty?
Uh, have you checked
the bathroom?
Oh.
-Didn't you say no animals?
-That's Lorraine.
She's been looking for that cat
as long as I've been here.
Well, I've just...
I've had a really long day
and I really need the bed.
First timer?
-Is there booze in that bag?
-Oh, no.
I haven't had a drink
for seven months.
(uplifting music playing)
Here's a list of the "dos"
and "do-nots."
If I catch you
with as much as an aspirin
that you haven't cleared
with me, you're done.
It's a privilege,
not a right, to be here.
-You got it?
-Got it.
But do you got it?
Got it.
Okay.
Wake-up's at 7:00.
Breakfast is 7:30.
We try to be gone
before morning Mass.
That's your cot over there.
Any questions?
-No.
-Good.
Oh.
No porn.
We're on the Lord's Wi-Fi
down here. Okay?
(laughs)
(slow hopeful music playing)
(vibrates)
(woman humming)
-(humming continues)
-(woman coughs)
(woman snoring)
(phone vibrates)
(indistinct chatter)
You're the new girl?
(Amanda sighs)
-(knob turning)
-(shower running)
Is the water hot?
(Amanda) It's warm.
Well, that won't last long.
(dramatic beats)
So how long you been
sleeping in your car for?
Seven months.
Is it at least a nice ride?
It's a '91 Camry.
Oof. That's rough.
I just mean...
I can see sleeping
in a van or a trailer
but an old beater like that?
-Well...
-Yikes.
It's got four doors
and four wheels and it's mine.
You don't got any friends
you could crash with?
No. No, no.
What about family?
Uh, just my kid, Avery,
but they're out in Utah
-with their dad.
-Avery.
That's a cool name. I like it.
You gonna eat that?
Whoa, watch out.
They're eating for two.
Oh.
Yeah, of course. It's all yours.
How far along are you?
-Three proud months.
-Oh.
Boy or girl?
I let them decide.
(Denise) Well, I hope
they get better food
-than the shit they feed here.
-Oh.
(all laugh)
What are we laughing at?
Nothing.
I know a joke.
Shut the fuck up, Lorraine.
Fuck.
(Lorraine) Okay.
I do, though.
You, cut the singing at night.
You ain't Beyoncé,
this ain't your Hive.
(laughs)
Something fucking funny to you?
Yeah, I thought... I thought
that was pretty funny.
Lorraine.
-Do the honors.
-Oh, yeah.
I pledge allegiance to the flag
of the United States of America
and to the Republic
for which it stands,
one nation, under God,
indivisible,
with liberty
and justice for all.
Alright, ladies.
Don't forget we have a Big Book 12-step
study tonight in the meeting room.
All are welcome.
Some are court-ordered.
You know who you are.
Don't make me come
looking for you.
You got about 20 minutes to
finish chow and clear the space.
Don't forget your bus passes.
They're up front.
They are for finding work.
Not trouble.
'Cause the Lord helps those
who what?
-Helps themselves.
-(all) Helps themselves.
Let's get to it.
-Let's get to it.
-(indistinct chatter)
Have you seen my boots?
(Nova humming)
Hey. Hey! Give me my boots back!
Give me...
Give me my fucking boots back!
-Fuck you talking about?
-Give me my boots!
-You fucking crazy--
-Really?
(grunts)
-(Amanda groans)
-(Barb) Jocelyn!
-Huh?
-I told you
there are rules
and consequences.
I know what you've been through,
but it does not excuse this.
Pack your bag.
Take your last bus pass.
Hey, hey. She didn't mean
to take my boots.
It was a misunderstanding.
It's a misunderstanding.
-(exhales)
-You're done here.
(exhales)
(gentle music playing)
(door opens and closes)
You gonna sit there all day?
Nope.
I'm gonna sit here all week.
'Cause my hearing
is not until Monday.
What happened to your nose?
What happened to your face?
(Cliff) Excuse me?
Well, it looks like
you could've been handsome.
Oh.
Yeah, if you just took
better care of yourself.
-It's called sunscreen.
-(dog barking)
(music continues)
(music fades)
(indistinct dispatch radio
chatter)
What's... What's this for again?
TB. For stays over three nights,
the church mandates it.
-Thanks, Linda.
-Yep. No problem.
Any, uh, luck on the job hunt?
Oh, I got a little sidetracked
with getting assaulted
this morning
and, um, my car was stolen.
And I have a court date
in regards to that.
And once I get my car back...
I will be all over it.
I was interviewing for a job
-when my car was--
-Try this.
"Seattle's First Street Paper
Providing Economic
Opportunities For the Homeless."
It's called Real Change.
It's not fancy but it's honest.
You buy it for 60 cents,
sell it for $2.
You keep the difference.
-A buck 40.
-(scoffs) I know.
But I've seen it add up.
You'd be surprised.
Thanks, but I did not spend
all my money
on a vet tech license
to become a paperboy.
When I get my car back,
I'm gonna get back out there
and get on the job market
like I was before.
That may take a while.
I know, but I have a plan.
You know what God does
when he hears about our plans?
-He laughs.
-(laughs) Well...
For a guy that doesn't exist,
that's pretty fucking rude.
And I'll let him know myself
next time you make us pray.
Listen, Amanda, people like us
need to stay busy.
To have a sense of purpose
to our days.
(scoffs)
Without my purpose here,
I'd still be robbing Bartells
for Roxies.
-(gasps)
-(Barb laughs)
Yeah, you think
you're surprised,
you should've seen my colleagues
at the law firm
when the cops marched in
and put handcuffs on me.
(sighs) Twenty-five years
of paralegal work down the drain
in one...
profoundly humiliating moment.
My pension? Vaporized.
And I was lucky.
I had a sympathetic judge.
Yeah, I got
into a diversion program.
As long as I stayed clean,
I stayed out of jail.
So, you see, I didn't have
to lose everything.
(exhales)
But I didn't have the guts
to be honest about
how bad things had gotten
'til it was too late.
Hm?
So...
(gentle music playing)
We all need a purpose.
I have a purpose.
It's to get my damn car back.
(Gail) Good evening.
Soap and a washcloth?
(Denise) Get that prison shit
out of here.
It's not mandatory.
It's just a complimentary offer.
No, it is fucking
sidewalk chalk, Gail.
Look, you wanna draw a line
around a dead body,
that is what you use.
(sighs) Come here.
Gail, wait. Castile soap.
It's scented with flowers
and herbs.
'Cause anything else, you're just
stripping your skin of the natural oils.
(chatter)
(Nova) Still reading?
Yeah, just looking
at some case law.
Trying to, you know,
brush up before my hearing.
Case law? Making any sense?
You know, when you slow down,
it actually makes
a ton of sense.
You're gonna crush that hearing.
(Amanda chuckles)
-You think so?
-Well, I don't.
Just because you take notes
with a pink pen,
it doesn't make you Elle Woods.
You a big fan
of Legally Blonde?
(Denise) Hell yes.
One and Two. It's underrated.
They've been teasing
the third one for years,
but I'll believe it
when I see it.
Listen.
Look, I'm not tryin' to hurt
your feelings or nothin'
but you're just wasting
your time with this lawsuit.
(smacks lips)
Okay, well, thank you.
That's good to know.
No, seriously.
We have all had a court case.
And we know how this goes.
You're one of us now, sis.
You're homeless
and that's about as bad
as being Black
or Brown in this country.
I'm telling you, buddy,
you wanna do the safari thing,
you do not want to do Kenya.
Too many tourists, too crowded,
too many Europeans.
Tanzania, baby!
It's gonna be epic.
(man on phone) Hell yeah,
it's gonna be epic!
-I am so looking forward to it.
-Huh? What the...?
Another lawsuit?
You gotta be shitting me. No.
No, no. Go away!
I'm telling you, buddy.
Tanzania.
-It's the way to go.
-(man on phone) Yeah.
I wanna see a cheetah
take down a wildebeest.
-Rawr! (laughs)
-(man on phone) Dude! Yeah!
(judge) Amanda Ogle
versus Kaplan Towing.
-Sorry.
-Case 305B7. Please step forward.
Hello... (clears throat)
...Your Honor.
Uh...
Are you appearing pro se?
Without a lawyer.
Oh, yes. Uh, yes.
And the defendant,
Kaplan Towing.
Didn't bother to show up.
Okay, Miss Ogle.
Do you have a statement?
Yes, Your Honor. I do. Um...
"I stand before you today
as the victim of two crimes.
First, my car was stolen as I
was attempting to seek a job
at a veterinarian establishment.
Second, my car was towed
by the defendant, Kaplan Towing,
and they extorted me
for hundreds--"
(judge) Extorted?
That's a strong word.
I know. That's why I picked it.
"They extorted me
for many hundreds of dollars
which is what brings me
here today."
Were any arrests made
in the alleged theft?
Alleged? I-I parked my car
in a parking lot
and it was stolen
and found on Mercer
the next day.
"Kaplan Towing, under their
exclusive contract with the city,
saw that my car
was immediately towed,
and I, the victim of a theft,
was slapped with a fee
of $273.20
plus $50 a day in storage fees
equaling $1,223,
all of which I have
the paperwork for right here."
May I see, please?
It's not every day
that someone enters my court
to sue a tow truck company...
over a 1991 Toyota Camry.
Is there sentimental value here?
Or, Miss Ogle,
are you experiencing
homelessness?
No. No, I am not,
Your Honor. No.
But, um...
minimum wage in this city
is 11 bucks an hour.
So if you're not a...
software developer
or, I don't know,
a judge, um,
you could be hit
with a fee like this,
and even if you're not homeless,
it could make you.
As the defendant
didn't have the courtesy
to appear in court today,
I hereby order the restitution
of your car
and the forfeit
of any related fees.
I'm sorry... What...
what did you say?
You won, Miss Ogle.
Congratulations.
-(chuckles)
-(uplifting music playing)
(cheers)
Whoo! Whoo!
Yes!
Whoo!
(dramatic beats)
Who's the best dog in the world?
(gasps) Just the dude
I was looking for.
You see this?
This is a court order
to release my car.
No fees, no fines,
no bullshit, just...
give me back my car, bitch!
(laughs)
(Amanda snorts)
(indistinct radio chatter)
What's wrong?
(sighs) I don't have your car,
Amanda.
What do you mean,
you don't have my car?
Well, who does?
Where's my car, Cliff?
Where's my car?
Where is it? I...
I have a court order to get it.
You gotta tell me where it is.
They sold it at an auction.
"They"? Who's "they"?
My bosses.
I mean, in their defense,
people like you
don't always come back
and get their cars.
"People like me"? What...
What does that mean?
How much did they sell it for?
How much did they get?
-(Cliff) $175.
-Goddamn it!
Sold it?
For $175?
How can they do this?
Is this legal?
I need my car!
This can't be happening!
Fuck!
(soft tense music playing)
(truck backup alarm beeping
nearby)
(music fades)
(man) Goddamn, Amanda.
Where the hell have you been?
Around.
(man) You ain't cheating on us,
are you?
(chuckles) Maybe.
(man) You look good.
What you having?
-First round's on the house.
-(sucks teeth)
-Double vodka rocks.
-You got it.
("On the Long Way Down" by
Paulsen-Shepler playing in bar)
♪ Hey there, friend
Are you at your end... ♪
Cheers.
♪ ...in this highway-gas-pump
town? ♪
(exhales)
(sniffs)
♪ Don't take the short way out ♪
♪ But until I'm through
I'll be here for you ♪
♪ On the long way down ♪
(music fades)
That's far enough.
Jesus Christ, Barb!
Oh my God, the bat?
Jesus is asleep, Amanda.
As is the rest of his flock.
Uh... I...
(slurring) I'm very sorry
that I'm late again. I...
I was out looking for work.
At the bottom of a bottle?
I am not drunk!
Uh, I'm-I'm exhausted.
(sighs) If you could just...
just cut me some slack,
uh, I just need to sleep.
You know?
Can you please
just let me sleep?
Please! Fuck! Why...
Just 'cause you're such
a lonely bitch
doesn't mean the rest of us
have to be too.
Come on!
Can you just not be such
a fucking hard-ass?
There are rules
and there are consequences.
Get out.
(dramatic music playing)
You brought this on yourself.
(siren blaring)
Lady! You need a place
to stay tonight?
I got a station wagon
around the corner.
(laughs) Oh, shit.
These streets ain't meant
for Little Red Riding Hood.
We got too many Big Bad Wolves
around here.
Eat shit, pal.
Come on. I'm just playing.
Okay, look.
Someone like you deserves
some comfort for the night.
I'm not like those hustlers
at the wharf.
I'm all about the deals. Look.
I can put you in a Sebring.
Five bucks a night,
$30 for the week.
That's me giving you
a free night.
And it's got power locks.
Plenty of room in the backseat.
You got a '91 blue Toyota Camry?
Seen one of those recently?
I don't fuck around
with compact cars.
My tenants like legroom. Look.
I got an RV around the corner.
Want to throw a little party?
Put your legs up?
-Huh?
-No.
(over phone) Where the fuck
is my car, Cliff?
Where the fuck is my car?
(dog barking)
(slurring)
Hello, it's Amanda Ogle.
I'm so sorry.
I received your message.
Um, I had a family...
just a small, like, tragedy
and I couldn't get there
but I... I had an incident
with my car.
But as soon
as I get my car back,
which I think is going to be
pretty soon...
But I really,
I just have to say,
I really wanted the job.
It was so cute in there with all
of those dogs.
It was so sweet
and I was so... I love animals.
I want to open
an animal hospital one day.
-(continues indistinctly)
-(somber music playing)
Ah!
(over phone) This is Amanda Ogle
in regards to her '91 Camry!
Thank you!
(car horns honking)
(dramatic music playing)
(dramatic music intensifies)
(music fades)
(vehicles passing by)
(car horn blares)
(breathing heavily)
(grunts)
(dramatic beats)
(phone vibrates)
(Amanda in voice-over) I won't
make it to Utah for Christmas.
I'll-- I'm so sorry.
I'll explain later.
(soft dramatic music plays)
(exhales deeply)
-(ship horn blowing)
-(seagulls squawking)
(Kevin) Good morning.
I will have
a white chocolate mocha, please.
What size?
We got 12-ounce, 16-ounce,
20-ounce, 24-ounce, 32-ounce.
Uh, small is good.
(mumbles) Oh, sorry. Oh.
-(car horn honks)
-Sorry about that. (sighs)
Uh, here.
Can I ask you something?
Do they offer you a pension here
by any chance?
Or at least some sort
of savings plan?
Good morning, Debbie.
Any calls?
Not that I'm aware of.
Did you check the voicemail?
Yes.
So no calls?
Uh, I can't say that for sure.
There may have been some callers
before I got here
that didn't leave messages.
Okay.
-Uh, Debbie?
-Yeah?
Who's the woman passed out
on my desk?
(Debbie) Oh, uh...
Oh, she says she knows you.
She had your business card.
I don't think she's well.
(bright, upbeat music playing)
Uh... (clears throat)
Excuse me.
Ma'am? (sniffs)
Ma'am? Hello?
-(gasps)
-Oh, geez!
Ugh...
-Uh...
-Do you know where you are?
My name is Kevin Eggers
and you're in my office.
Can I help you?
(splutters)
Have you got a light?
You're not allowed to smoke
in here.
-Okay.
-How about a glass
of filtered water?
I, um... (smacks lips)
We met a few weeks ago
at the courthouse.
-Right.
-Right?
You were not a big fan
of lawyers,
or maybe of me.
Right. Exactly.
-And yet here you are.
-Right.
(clears throat) So I have a plan
to get my car back,
but I really need your help.
So I got a court order
from the tow truck company
to give me back my car,
and they were gonna forfeit
all of the fees.
They were gonna give it
back to me. I got that.
The judge granted that to me.
It was all good.
And then I got there,
but they had already sold
my car.
-So I have all of my notes here.
-Okay. Slow down.
-I'm prepared...
-You have a court order?
Yes, I have a court order.
It's right here.
You can read it.
You filed this pro se?
What the fuck does that mean?
Uh, it means I'm impressed.
That's all.
Okay. Well, I-I ha-- I...
That's nice,
but I have a whole plan here
I'd like to run past you.
I was thinking, I was reading up
about this thing
about pleading
the state's Attorney General.
What do you think?
Well, okay, um,
that's interesting,
but maybe a little premature.
I'm gonna need some time
to look up on your case
a little bit.
Um, maybe we can reconnect later
in the week or early next week.
-Uh, Debbie can set a time.
-Yeah.
Oh, sure. Yeah.
Fuck, you know what?
Just call me
at the Four Seasons,
'cause that's where I'm staying.
That's where I stay.
I have a massage at four,
so, you know...
-You're joking.
-Yeah. No. Know what?
I know when someone's
blowing me off.
I can take my water,
I can take my stuff.
You know, I'm good.
But you gave me your card.
But I'm fine.
Thank you.
Pardon me.
Wait.
I do wanna help.
I fully understand
that she's not exactly
an ideal resident,
but I can promise you,
we've been having
some very important
conversations
in the past 24 hours.
Listen, we are
a high bar shelter
for a reason, okay?
And I have to maintain
that standard.
(Kevin) I wholly respect that,
and you do
a wonderful job with that.
But she's had a difficult time
here in the past, however,
just one more time back and...
Kevin, let's just go,
let's go. Okay?
This is a waste of time.
I told you. Come on.
There are rules...
(both) ...and there are
consequences.
Yes, I know. Blah, blah, blah.
She's willing
to let you come back.
She is? You are?
I told her that as my client,
and as my beloved aunt...
that I could vouch for you
and your worthiness
of a second chance.
And then I told
this little twerp
that I would consider it
on my terms.
You attend my Big Book study.
-Every week?
-Every day.
-Oh, Jesus.
-And you can't just drink tea.
I need to see
active participation.
It's the only way
this program is effective.
One of us is a bit of a
control freak, and it's not me.
She's not serious about this.
She's not even sober right now.
She will be,
I promise you.
(Kevin sighs)
If we have a chance
to win this case,
you have to remain stable
and sober.
This is how you get there.
I know he's not your nephew.
He's a lawyer, Barb!
They're all liars!
-Hmm.
-(Amanda groans)
(bright, upbeat music plays)
Hi, this is Kevin Eggers
calling for Martin LaRosa,
just to let him know
that he is in fact
in contempt of court.
Hey, hon, it's Mom. Just, um...
Just calling,
just checking in, okay?
Love you. Call me. Call me.
I'm worried that my friends
only like me because I drink.
Oh.
With your newfound sobriety,
you could set your friends
on their own path.
(snorts, bleats)
You sound like a whole gaggle
of sheep.
Constructive input only, Denise.
(Denise) Come on. Claire...
You are not an addict.
No?
She's not an addict.
My girl is old and bored.
-Uh-uh.
-(Denise) I'm sorry. Come on.
It's not like
it's you and me, Barb.
It is not like she woke up
in a crack house
-with a dick in her mouth.
-That's enough, Denise.
Oh, why? Why? It's true.
(Barb) Well, that's not
how this works. Okay?
If Denise is going to pass
judgment,
then she needs to share
something about herself.
Something honest.
Okay, fine.
(breathes deeply)
Hi, I'm Denise,
and I am an addict
and an alcoholic.
Hi, Denise.
I moved to Seattle
11 years ago for school.
Two kids and two divorces later,
I'm still here.
I picked up some...
bad habits, exercise and coke.
-(Barb) Mmm.
-Not a great combo.
And that led to steroids
and speed.
And...
now I, uh... (chuckles)
...just, I really hate needles,
so I smoked everything.
-E-even the steroids?
-Especially the steroids.
And then one day...
(clears throat)
...my second husband
kicked me out,
I lost my kids,
and now I'm here.
The end.
(Barb) Colorful as always.
Well, it's the fucking truth.
And the truth
shall set you free.
(Denise) Hmm.
How about you, Amanda?
I'm good.
You've been back for a week
and have yet to share.
Like I said, I'm good.
She's good, Barb.
(Barb) All right, Brenda,
you're up.
Hi, I'm Brenda
and I'm an alcoholic.
(all) Hi, Brenda.
-How you doing?
-Hi, Brenda.
He's in Palm Springs? Terrific.
Tell him Kevin Eggers
sends him his best.
(woman on phone)
I'll give him the message.
(sighs)
Amanda, can I speak
with you? Now.
I already know
what you're going to say.
That it's not enough for me
just to attend the meetings,
that I also have to work
the steps.
But I have been down
this road before
and it doesn't work for me.
I'm sorry to break it
to you, honey,
but you are not special.
The way in which you are a drunk
and a disappointment to yourself
and the people you love
is just the same
as everybody else in that room.
(sighs) Okay,
I got it. I got it.
-Can I please just go and--
-But do you get it, Amanda?
I can't see that you get it.
-Yes, I got it.
-You got it?
I got it. Okay?
I told you, I got it.
How many friends do you have...
-Ugh.
-...if you were to count?
None? 'Cause your daughter
doesn't count. She's a kid,
-that's too much for her--
-Don't talk about my daughter!
That is none of your business.
(Barb) Okay.
This whole, dukes up,
Rosie the Riveter thing
makes sense out there
in the world.
Dealing with all those
government agencies
and a legal system
that doesn't see you as anything
but a problematic number
on a sheet of statistics.
I get it.
You need your walls up
doing battle with that.
I get it.
But in here with us,
you gotta take those walls down
and let us in.
You can make it. I-I see it.
But I promise you,
you cannot make it alone.
None of us can.
I'm just really tired.
Can I please go
-and lay down?
-Go. Go.
(somber music playing)
(loud, discordant traffic noise)
(Amanda gasps)
(panting)
(gasping)
(light classical music playing
on speakers)
(phone vibrating)
Goddamn it, Brenda. It's Friday.
This better be important.
(Brenda) Sorry, Mr. LaRosa,
but some lawyer from the NWCLC
keeps calling.
(stammers) NW what?
(Brenda) The Northwest
Consumer Law Center.
Oh, shit. Yeah.
I know who this asshole is.
Put him through.
(Brenda) Okay. Hold on.
Mr. LaRosa, we finally connect.
Is this about
another towed vehicle?
No, sir. This is about
the same towed vehicle.
Judge Smith ordered
my client's car returned.
We have a court order. We'd like
her car back plus damages.
Damages? What,
for that piece of crap?
Uh, Mr. LaRosa,
that car was her home.
All right, so you want my client
to pay damages
because they towed a car
that's some fuckin' bum
was squatting in?
With all due respect,
Mr. LaRosa,
my client is not a bum.
She owns the car.
No, she doesn't. Not any longer.
Look, it-- You know,
why didn't she just...
go to a... go to a shelter,
you know?
It's gotta be better
than sleeping in a car. Come on.
Mr. LaRosa,
I don't need to tell you
how bad the optics are here
for you or your client.
All right, kid.
Where are you from?
Lewiston, Idaho.
Oh, Jesus. Worse than I thought.
(breathes deeply)
A young kid from Potato Town
takes on Big Bad Corporation,
becomes a hometown hero,
champion of the underserved.
All 25 people
you went to high school with
buy you beer and give you
a blow job at the reunion?
I hope so.
I hope it was fuckin' worth it
because I'm gonna bankrupt
your shitty little nonprofit
in discovery.
I'm gonna turn you upside down
like a fuckin' chicken,
slit your throat
and bleed you out.
(receiver slams)
(receiver clicks)
(phone vibrating)
Hello?
Ave, it's me.
Please don't hang up.
So you're tricking me now?
Ah, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Ave. I just...
Ah. Just out of options.
I wanted to hear your voice.
I miss you.
Not enough to come see me
for Christmas.
You always do this.
It's-it's different, honey.
-I-I swear.
-It's never different.
I'm sorry, Ave.
How-how are your projects going?
How are you?
How are the costumes?
Um, I'm not gonna do it.
(scoffs)
Are you kidding? W-why?
I decided it's a waste of time
and it's stupid,
and I-I'm not gonna do it.
Ave... Ave, what's up?
My designs suck anyway.
They're amateur.
They're not good enough
for competition
and other people have like
all the money in the world
to spend on it, and-and--
Ave, I wanna help. I-I-I do.
I'm gonna help.
Why aren't you coming home
for Christmas?
Can you tell me
the actual truth or...
-Drinking again or...?
-No, no, no. I'm sober.
I-I-I'm good. I, uh...
money's a little tight.
I'm just taking
a few extra hours at the clinic
and I'm a little slammed.
That's all, honey.
But I'm gonna get there.
I just... I just can't get there
soon enough.
Yeah, well...
See you never, I guess.
-Ave, Ave, wait.
-I needed you.
(call ends)
-Hey. Thank you so much.
-Mm-hmm.
-Thank you.
-No problem.
-Real Change?
-No thanks.
-Real Change.
-No.
(siren wailing nearby)
(phones ringing)
(brakes squeak)
(funky, intriguing music
playing)
(camera shutter clicking)
(music fades)
♪ Deck the halls
with boughs of holly ♪
♪ Fa-la-la-la-la, la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 'Tis the season to be jolly ♪
-♪ Fa-la-la-la-la...
-Oh...
-(Denise) Mmm.
-I like your hat.
-Well... ho, ho, ho.
-(chuckles)
-Ho!
-(laughter)
I can't believe we're stuck
in this shithole on Christmas.
-Ugh.
-Didn't you wanna sing?
Hi, everyone.
I'd like to welcome to the stage
one of our very own.
Nova Gutierrez.
-(Gail giggles)
-(all cheer)
Whoo!
♪ Have yourself
♪ A merry little Christmas ♪
♪ Let your heart be light
♪ From now on, our troubles
♪ Will be out of sight ♪
♪ Have yourself
♪ A merry little Christmas ♪
♪ Make the yuletide gay ♪
♪ From now on, our troubles
♪ Will be miles ♪
♪ Away (holds note, vocalizes)
-Thanks.
-♪ Here we are
♪ As in olden days ♪
♪ Happy golden days ♪
♪ Of yore ♪
♪ Faithful friends
♪ Who are dear to us ♪
♪ Gather near to us
Jemma! Jemma!
-♪ Once more
-Mommy!
(indistinct)
(Nova vocalizing)
Look at you.
-♪ Through the years ♪
-(indistinct)
♪ We all will be together ♪
-♪ If the fates...
-Merry Christmas.
What are you doing here?
♪ ...allow... ♪
Well, there's news.
Pretty great news, in fact,
and some bad, but you know.
What's the great?
Found your car,
filed a motion for its return.
Kaplan complied and they are
buying back the car.
-Oh, my God!
-(both laughing)
-I know!
-They bought back my car?
-It doesn't mean it's yours yet,
but it's a step
in the right direction.
-Oh, my God!
-Thought it might cheer you up.
-No, I don't smoke.
-Yeah, no shit.
I just wanna offer you something
for Christmas, to say thank you.
Oh, man! So when can I see it?
Where-where are they keeping it?
What's the...
That's kind of where we get
to the bad news a little bit.
Okay. What's the bad news?
Quit stalling.
-Tell me.
-This is gonna take
a little bit of time. I...
I don't know how long, but...
you will have to be patient,
and I know that's not really
-your biggest strength.
-Okay. I can be patient.
Can I go see it at least?
-Where are they keeping it?
-This is what I'm talking about.
-I'm doing the best I can.
-Can I see it?
It's just paperwork, right?
Crossing Ts, dotting Is.
It's just going to take time.
-(inhales deeply)
-You holding up okay?
Um, I've been better,
but you know...
It's really great
you're keeping up
with the meetings
and everything.
-All that support...
-Mmm.
-...seems like they're helping.
-Mm-hmm. Yep.
Eyeballs everywhere,
so staying sober.
I'm... really sorry
you didn't make it
to see Avery for Christmas.
Me too. Mm.
You know, I tried,
but without my car, I'm...
(clicks tongue)
...I'm a deadbeat.
You're not a deadbeat.
You just...
made a few wrong turns.
(chuckles)
Who hasn't done that? Right?
(dramatic beats)
(soft dramatic music playing)
(phone vibrates)
(cheery music plays)
(dog barking)
-Is that the heart?
-Mm-hmm.
Is this really happening?
Is there another person
in my body?
Exciting.
Real-life science fiction.
I have no money, no family.
Everyone I've ever counted on
has let me down.
How am I going to take care
of a baby?
I'm so scared.
I don't think I can do this.
I don't think
I can do this alone.
Okay...
One step at a time. (murmurs)
(Amanda breathes deeply)
One day at a time.
("Flatlands" by Chelsea Wolfe
playing)
♪ I want flatlands
I never cared about ♪
♪ Money and all its friends
♪ I want flatlands ♪
(dramatic beats)
♪ I want flatlands
♪ I don't want precious stones ♪
♪ I never cared about ♪
♪ Anything you've ever owned ♪
♪ I want flatlands
♪ I want simplicity ♪
♪ I need your arms
♪ Wrapped hard around me ♪
-Anything else?
-That's it.
-(man) Make this last all week.
-(Denise) Fine.
(song ends)
(car drives off)
(Nova) Can you sit still?
Sorry, I'm trying.
(dramatic beats)
I thought lawyer dude
told you to be patient.
I just wanna see how much.
(Nova) Are you sure about that?
It can't hurt to take a look.
(bottle squelching)
What the fuck?!
(dramatic music playing)
Where is he?!
(Kevin) Here, take a look
at the section on PSST.
-Why am I being charged...
-Amanda?
...$18,267?
Why didn't you tell me?
I just found this out yesterday
myself.
How could you not know?
I knew we were dealing
with bad people.
I didn't know they were
gonna take it this far.
But how can they do this to me
when I have a court order
to get back my car
without any fees?
How can they do this to us?
We're dealing
with legal bullies here.
This is what they do.
Charge you with fees,
try to countersue you,
all to try to make us
drop this case.
They're in contempt of court.
We will beat them.
I know it's frustrating,
but we just have to remain calm.
Calm? We are not living
in a shelter.
We did not miss Christmas
with our daughter,
and we do not have a bill
for $18,000.
Hey!
What are you doing?!
Did that lady
just steal your bike?
I think she did.
Can I have a white chocolate
mocha please?
Small.
(Amanda) Where's my car, Cliff?
-Oh, shit.
-I know it's in there!
-Take it easy.
-God damnit. Fuck you!
-Give me my car!
-Slow down.
-You're gonna get hurt. Ooh!
-(groans)
(Cliff) Oh, shit.
(groaning)
-Are you okay?
-(groans)
(groaning)
(dramatic music playing)
(gasps)
Yes, yes, yes! Yeah, I did it!
I did it! (breathes deeply)
I sold my first design.
(exhales)
-(line rings)
-(sighs)
(man) Animal Hospital.
Hi, this is Avery Ogle.
Um, I need to speak
with my mom, Amanda.
(man) Does she have a pet
under our care?
(sharp exhale) Um, no.
She works there.
Um, Amanda Ogle?
(man) Yeah, we don't have anyone
that works here by that name.
(soft dramatic music playing)
Okay. Um, well, thank you. Bye.
(door opens)
Ooh, there she is.
That stupid fucking bitch.
Who the fuck are you
to tell Barb my business? Huh?
You're using again.
I'm sorry. (stammers)
I was just worried, D.
You're no better than me.
You know that, right?
I just wanted you
to get some help.
-Oh, you wanted me gone?
-No! No.
Well, you got it.
-(laughs)
-No, no, no. No.
D, I just wanted you
to get some help.
That's it. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm...
(chuckles)
(dramatic music continues)
(music intensifies)
Ah... (huffs air)
Next case.
(Kevin) Do you have any idea
where he is?
He was supposed to be here
an hour ago.
(Brenda) Sorry.
Not at the moment.
(Kevin) Is there another attorney I can
speak to who would take this seriously?
Mr. LaRosa either
doesn't show up in court
or he keeps filing for delays.
We're talking about
someone's home.
(Martin grunts)
Have you ever heard of kindness?
(Avery) Hi. I can't get
to the phone right now.
Feel free to either leave
a message or text me. Thank you.
Hey, Ave, it's Mom.
Just call me back, okay?
Miss you.
(phone dings)
(Avery in voice-over)
I called the vet office.
I know you're not working there.
(phone dings)
I'm never talking to you again.
You're a liar and a drunk,
and I don't need you
in my life anymore.
(somber music playing)
Yes. Hi, this is Amanda Ogle.
This is Amanda Ogle.
Hello, this is Amanda Ogle.
Cliff, it's Amanda.
Call me back.
You have my '91 blue...
...Toyota Camry.
My '91 Camry!
Cliff, it's Amanda.
Call me back.
Hey, it's Mom. Call me back.
License number ADQ-377.
ADQ...
No, Q. Q.
Ogle.
O as in orange, G as in Greg,
L as in Lucy.
Yes, yes, yes.
Hey, it's me,
just trying you again.
Uh, call me back. Okay?
Miss you.
It's been over 171 days.
I am calling to get my car back!
If you could please return
my call...
Fuck you!
(dramatic music playing)
(phone chimes)
(dramatic beats)
(music builds, fades)
Hi, my name is Amanda
and I'm an alcoholic.
(all) Hi, Amanda.
Um...
I'm not very good at this.
I don't like to share. Um...
I'm terrible at it. In fact,
-this is my first share.
-(woman) Okay.
I've been lurking in the back
of these rooms for years,
um, like some kind of creep.
But, um, anyway...
here I go. Uh...
I took my first drink at 11.
Um, let's just say
some fucked up shit happened
when I was ten, um...
Drinking helped for a time
'til it didn't,
uh, until I woke up
and just realized
that I lost everything
that mattered, and...
a lot of stuff
that didn't matter too.
Um, and then five years ago,
I had a car accident
and I got given opioids
for pain management,
um, which I liked.
And then...
uh, I started drinking.
And, um, every single day,
I would just wake up
and reach for the bottle
that I kept close to me.
And then three years ago,
I tried to take my life.
Uh, I took so many pills,
the doctor was as surprised
as I was that I woke up.
(light chuckle) And then, um...
And then shortly after that,
I lost my daughter.
It was the only thing
that really mattered. (sobs)
And, uh... (sobs) I was just...
I didn't trust myself
with her anymore,
so I had to let her go.
And I still have some days
where I think it would be better
if I just jumped off
a bridge, but...
(crying)
...I... I...
I wanna live.
I wanna live
and I wanna get her back.
And, um...
(sniffles) ...I know,
I fully, fully know
that I can't do that alone.
(group members murmur)
I can't do that alone
and I need help.
-(woman) That's right.
-So, uh... thank you.
(applause)
And that's my share.
Thank you.
(bright music playing)
-Thank you, Amanda.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
(light chuckle)
Amanda shared, Katie.
You could share.
-Yeah.
-(all laugh)
-(light song plays)
-♪ Hop, hop, bunny, hop
-(song fades)
(Amanda) You really need a car.
I had a bike. You stole it.
I borrowed it.
Uh, borrowing would suggest
we had an agreement.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm sorry. That is sarcasm.
Something that I am getting
sober from
because it's avoidant,
and I'm trying to be present
in my life right now...
Is this going somewhere?
Let's get to work.
(scoffs)
You're not a lawyer, Amanda.
These assholes need to pay.
So, you know...
Let's face it, we could both use
each other's help.
Okay.
("Finger In Your Eye"
by YACHT playing)
♪ One of these days
you're gonna give up ♪
♪ But you're not gonna do it
'til your enemy does ♪
♪ One of these days
you're gonna give up ♪
Yes!
♪ But you're not gonna do it ♪
♪ 'Til your enemy does ♪
♪ Finger in your eye
Finger in your eye ♪
♪ Won't you see me better ♪
-♪ Ooh-ooh
-(stapler clicking)
♪ Finger in your eye
Finger in your eye ♪
♪ Helps you to remember ♪
Where is he?
Where is he? Where...
Oh, fuck!
-...is...
-Fore!
-...he?
-Oh, (bleep).
Argh!
I've got coffee.
Wonderful. Wonderful.
Right there is perfect.
-Here.
-Thank you.
♪ Finger in your eye ♪
♪ Helps you to remember ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ Finger in your eye ♪
♪ Won't you see me better? ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ Take it from a friend ♪
♪ Making your amends ♪
♪ Not as fun as when you lose
your temper ♪
-♪ Listening is free
-(humming)
♪ If you're hearing me ♪
♪ Choosy but I gotta be
a beggar ♪
♪ So do what you do
but don't do it too much ♪
Yes. Hello,
this is Kevin Eggers.
-Uh, please hold.
-Hey, you asshole.
-No!
-You have had my car.
Excuse me?
I'm sorry.
That was really weird.
Um, yes, I can hold.
Give her the car back!
Fuck off.
♪ Won't you see me better? ♪
♪ Finger in your eye
Finger in your eye ♪
♪ Helps you to remember ♪
-(Barb) There are rules.
-No, I got it.
-You got it?
-Thanks.
(song ends abruptly)
(person coughs)
("America the Beautiful"
playing on piano)
(dogs barking)
(Amanda) He's so beautiful.
Oh, my goodness.
Is that okay? "He"?
Yes, he's a boy
until he's old enough to decide.
Ooh.
Are you ready to pick a name?
-Did you bring our list?
-I did.
(chuckling) Hey.
Taylor?
-No.
-(baby coos)
Jodie?
Ew, definitely not.
That was Denise's choice.
(Nova chuckles) Next.
Maverick or...
Kilmer? Ah.
-She loves Top Gun.
-(chuckles)
What about... Navy?
Nova and Navy.
I don't know. I...
I don't think
we're gonna find anything.
Hey, what about this?
Kinda cute?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I'm going to court,
not American Bandstand.
I need to look professional.
Serious.
Okay, okay, fine.
Maybe I'll keep it.
Put a slit up the back.
Give Brett some easy access.
Oh, you guys are talking?
Talking? No.
-Fucking, sometimes.
-(chuckles)
I'm not horny for him.
I'm just...
grateful he lets me see my kids.
-Well, that's one way to do it.
-Mmm.
Avery's still not talking to me.
Look, keep at 'em.
They'll come around
if they got sense,
-which they do.
-I don't know.
They're very stubborn
and they are pissed.
Okay, put a pin in that.
What about this?
-Jacket, smart pencil skirt.
-Hmm.
You know it's giving,
"Your Honor,
you must listen to me."
I don't know.
Maybe I should just...
wear my own stuff, you know?
I might feel too uncomfortable.
How long you been uncomfortable?
Real question.
Look,
it doesn't matter what you wear.
You are Amanda Ogle.
And you are gonna get
your car back.
(chuckles)
Not just for you,
for all of us.
(sighs)
(phone vibrates)
We're finally going to court.
Is there anything you wanna add?
We went over this last time.
-I remember.
-The most important part
-is disregarding...
-We have a problem.
(sighs) Debbie.
We got a lot of problems.
Yeah. Uh, LaRosa is claiming
that it was Brent's Towing
that sold Amanda's car,
subcontractor of Kaplan,
thereby absolving them
of all damage.
But that's bullshit.
It's obviously the same company.
-That's not gonna hold up.
-(sighs)
No, but we still have
to fight it.
Which means what?
(sighs) More time, more money.
This is their game.
Give us enough BS pleadings
until we quit or go bankrupt.
But how can they get away
with this?
This is obviously, like, a scam.
I know it's not right,
but it is technically legal.
Well, in District Court anyway.
Let me know
if you need anything else.
Wait, what-what'd you say?
Let me know
if you need anything else.
No, no. About District Court.
Oh, no, I didn't say that.
I'm just repeating something
Kevin said the other day
about how if he'd filed
in Superior Court
instead of District Court
in the first place,
this all could have been
avoided. I...
I say live and learn, right?
(chuckles)
(upbeat, tense music playing)
So you fucked up. Just say it.
I didn't fuck up.
I just didn't realize
that these assholes would take
such advantage of you...
Why don't you just say
you fucked up
and you filed
in the wrong court,
and that's why we're tied up
in all of this crap?
Okay, sure.
Knowing what I know now,
I could have filed
in Superior Court,
-but we can't just assume--
-331 days without my car.
Kevin, I need to see my kid.
I-I've missed Christmas.
I've missed everything!
I-I haven't seen them
for over a year
and this all
could have been avoided
if you would just--
-You just say it.
-Fine.
If you want me to say
that I haven't had...
You made a mistake and you filed
in the wrong court!
And that is your job!
...then fine.
But you could at least give me
a little bit of credit
for dedicating months of my life
to a Camry
that is 40 pages of motion,
an hour per page.
I know this isn't worth
shit to you.
I know that. That's fine.
-Amanda--
-No, no, no!
Don't spend another hour on it!
(dramatic music playing)
(dramatic beats)
(truck backup alarm beeping
nearby)
(scoffs)
Excuse me. Who's the attorney
for Brent's Towing?
That would be me.
And you sued the wrong
fucking company.
I can't help you, kid.
(line beeps)
(phone ringing nearby)
(yells)
("Monster Stroll"
by Jocko playing)
♪ It was Halloween night
at the Castle Hall ♪
-♪ And everybody came... ♪
-(dog whimpers)
(over phone) Amanda,
Mike Patterson, Seattle Times.
Uh, it's inspiring to watch
someone like you
fight the system.
I'd like to talk to you.
I know Kevin called you,
but I still don't really
understand
why you wanna talk to me.
I mean, I think there could be
a story here.
Seattle woman pushed out
of her housing
fights back after becoming
a vehicle resident.
(chuckles) That's a cute term,
"vehicle resident."
I think most people would
probably have given up by now.
I need my car back.
I appreciate what you're trying
to do, but I am no hero.
I think most people
would disagree.
(soft music plays)
(dogs barking in distance)
(knocks on window)
Can I get my car back?
Well, I... I can't.
(train horn blaring)
(knocks on window)
-Yeah?
-Hi, Chowder.
Hi, Chowder.
-Say hi.
-Hi.
-Hi, Chowder.
-Aww.
Hey.
-(brake squeaks)
-(dog barking)
(soft music continues)
(dramatic beats)
(music fades)
(faint indistinct chatter)
-Hi.
-You look nice.
-Oh, thanks.
-(light chuckle)
-You ready?
-Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Let's go.
(indistinct chatter)
(Amanda sighs)
(bailiff) All rise.
You may be seated.
(judge) We're here
on the defendant's motion
for summary judgment.
On the docket,
we have Case KC18C,
Ogle versus Kaplan Towing.
Go ahead, counsel.
(Martin) Yes, Your Honor.
This really isn't necessary.
It's a waste
of the court's time.
The plaintiff has sued
the wrong defendant.
Then maybe you should implead
the right defendant
and seek indemnification.
Hey, well, happy to do it, kid.
But we'll need time.
Your Honor, how long does it
take to find your own company?
Brent's is a registered
subcontractor of Kaplan.
They're stalling
and have been for a year.
This is standard procedure.
Standard procedure, Your Honor,
as counsel puts it,
is a bill for $21,534.
Miss Ogle had every opportunity
to pay this fine from day one.
-She chose not to do so.
-I chose?
Your Honor, clearly Mr. LaRosa--
Is a fucking asshole!
-Hey, hey, hey!
-(overlapping shouting)
Miss Ogle, I won't have
outbursts in my courtroom.
I apologize, Your Honor.
But I said today
I would tell the truth
and that's the truth.
Your Honor...
I'm sorry, Your Honor.
I just wrote a few notes.
I just quickly wanna say, I...
"I didn't wanna call myself
homeless
when I first came to court
because I know what that means
to people like the defendant.
They wanna write us off as lazy,
sick nobodies,
not people who just fell
into bad luck
and didn't have a safety net
to catch us.
And I get it. It's easier
for you to just pretend
that we're lazy, sick nobodies.
But ever since my stolen car
got towed by the defendant
368 days ago,
I have spent
every one of those days
fighting to get it back.
I made over 200 phone calls,
Your Honor, to the tow yard.
I waited on hold
for hundreds of hours.
I spent five nights
on the street
and over 12 months in a shelter,
and the toughest part of all...
is that I haven't seen my kid
in over a year.
My car is how I got to my kid.
My car was my home
for over six months
before it was stolen.
That 1991 Camry is mine.
Trying to get it back is
the hardest job I've ever had,
and none of this happened
because I messed up."
And I have messed up
in my life, Your Honor,
but this situation with my car,
I swear to you,
this was not my fault.
"It all started because somebody
stole from me,
and I'm not talking about
the guy who jacked my car
and took it on a joyride
while I was at a job interview.
I'm talking about
what the defendant did to me
afterward.
Kaplan Towing
or-or Brent's Towing
or whatever shell
that they wanna hide under
is so much worse
than any small-time criminal
on the street.
These gangsters hold cars
for ransom
from people like me.
And if you complain about it,
they threaten you
and then they countersue you
into silence.
And instead of stopping them,
the city just helps them along,
handing them
sweetheart contracts
with no competition.
But unlike the defendant,
I'm not looking for a handout
from the city.
All I want is what is fair
and decent.
I'll never get back
everything I lost,
especially the time
that I lost with my kid.
But maybe today
I can get back some sense
that once in a while,
the system does the right thing
even for someone like me.
And I'm not asking
for an apology,
even though it would be nice.
All you have to do
is just give me my car back."
Thank you, Your Honor.
(applause)
(bright music playing)
(chuckling)
(Barb) Oh!
(Denise) Ooh,
looking good, Amanda.
-(Barb) Yeah.
-(chuckles)
(Amanda in voice-over) On my way.
I can't wait to see you.
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
Ha!
Ah!
Well, people are calling you
a hero, Amanda.
-Oh. (sniffles)
-It's true.
(sharp exhale)
You know, I, uh...
I did actually fuck up that one.
Oh, stop.
I fucked up so many things.
-Congratulations.
-Ah. (sniffles)
I, uh, I held onto
some of your things for you.
-Oh.
-I also fixed your muffler
and rotated the tires.
You do that for everybody?
Thank you.
I'll grab this.
Oh, thank you.
(sighs loudly, chuckles)
Oh!
Ha!
(breathes deeply)
(bag thuds)
Got my keys. (giggling)
Thank you. (murmurs, laughs)
(sniffles) Okay.
(grunts)
-(sighs)
-(ignition clicking)
(soft music playing)
(ignition clicks)
Hey, why the fuck
isn't the car starting?
Oh! I forgot to charge
the battery.
God damnit! Fuck!
(sighs deeply)
(sighs, sobs)
God damnit.
-Sorry.
-Fuck.
(sighs)
Okay, so do you have
a charger?
I-I could jump it.
-(Kevin) Oh, what the fudge.
-What the fuck.
("Multi-Family Garage Sale"
by YACHT playing)
Yeah, you-you can--
The needle is there.
You just... Your eyes are bad.
-Is it there?
-You can't see it? Yes. Yes.
The needle
is on the Space Needle.
-I must need glasses.
-(chuckling)
-Hi, Kevin.
-How's it going?
Can you see the needle
on top of the Space Needle?
-I can.
-Yeah.
Are we discussing
whether Amanda can or not?
-I cannot.
-(chuckling)
She was like, "Where'd it go?"
(laughing)
(indistinct chatter)
(indistinct chatter continues)
(upbeat instrumental music
playing)
(music fades)